# Pablo Andrés Hincapié Duque

# Java Developer

(+57) 3113590047
pablohincapie@hotmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/pablo-hincapie
https://github.com/pablohincapie
https://pablohincapie.github.io/home/

**Software engineer** with over 5+ years of experience in developing large-scale web applications, primarily using **Java-based** languages and **frameworks**. My passion for technology has allowed me to optimize processes and develop reliable, scalable, and user-friendly solutions, including the development of microservices and enterprise applications.

I have experience in object-oriented analysis and design, **backend** development, code refactoring, and improvements, as well as managing various database engines. Additionally, I have worked under **version control** methodologies and automated development processes, ensuring fast and reliable deliveries through **continuous integration** and delivery. I adapt well to **agile** environments and am focused on contributing to the development of innovative solutions while continuing to expand my knowledge of emerging technologies and modern development practices.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# GlobalLogic, Software Engineer — April 2022 - Present

GlobalLogic is a Hitachi Group company and a leader in digital product engineering. It helps its clients design and build innovative products, platforms, and digital experiences for the modern world.

- Participated in the creation of **20% of the new features** in the backlog for one of the largest banks in South America, enhancing user experience and functionality.
- Developed **over 5 new features** for the customer benefits and recognition site.
- Developed and migrated more **than 10 microservices** from a monolithic architecture, improving system scalability and performance.
- Provided technical support and developed new features for one of the fintech companies based in the United States.

**Tech-stack**: Java, Spring boot, Spring framework, Sql Server, Git, Azure Devops, Jira, JUnit, TypeScript, Css, Html, Jenkis.

#### Accion Point, Software Engineer — January 2022 - April 2022

Accion Point is a software factory specialized in the development, configuration, and implementation of business solutions based on information technology.

- · Reduced the number of bugs and issues reported by the client by 35%, enhancing overall software reliability.
- Developed new modules and components, achieving a 30% advance in project timelines.
- Created Java interfaces and managed source code configuration.
- Developed frontend components using TypeScript, HTML, and CSS.

**Tech Stack**: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Framework, SQL Server, Git, GitHub, Jira, Postman, JUnit, TypeScript, CSS, HTML, JBoss, Jenkis.

#### Accenture, Software Engineer — October 2020 - December 2021

Accenture is a multinational company providing strategic consulting, technology services, and outsourcing.

- Reduced client-**reported bugs and issues by 30**%, supporting the development team in implementing tools like Sonar and Coverity for code quality assurance.
- Developed new modules and components, achieving a 50% advance in project timelines.
- Created Java interfaces and managed source code configuration, ensuring smooth integration and deployment processes.

Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Framework, Sybase, Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Postman, JUnit, Sonar, Jenkis.

#### Quipux, Software Developer —November 2018-October, 2020

Colombian company the focus is the creation of sustainable, safe, and friendly mobility solutions.

- Modified existing software, reducing and correcting bugs reported by the client by 40%.
- Developed software modules based on customer's requirements during a release the performance Improved by 45% with refactoring code.
- Worked closely with customers to efficiently resolve issues and improved 3 days less.

Tech-stack: Java, EJB, Oracle, git, Jira, postman, sonar, Jenkis

# Konecta, Systems Analyst — September 2013 - November 2018

Konecta is a multinational company focused on excellence in customer experience management and innovation.

- Improved and created 35% of new features in the client module, enhancing system functionality.
- Participated in all 4 stages of software development, contributing to analysis, design, implementation, and testing.
- Maintained a system for documenting code, increasing documentation coverage by 80% and ensuring accurate tracking of software developments.
- Implemented scalable systems for three primary departments: human resources, marketing, and supply chain, improving operational efficiency.

Tech Stack: Java, HTML, CSS, Oracle, Jira, Postman.

# Ordenamiento Profesionales Optimizados (OPA), Developer — January 2013 - June 2013

OPA provides customized IT solutions to integrate and improve business operations.

- Developed and designed software programs for financial tracking and reporting, optimizing user efficiency and reducing report module **delays by up to 10**%.
- Applied over **50 financial and mathematical concepts** to enhance software functionality and track changes in existing programs.

Tech Stack: Visual FoxPro, SQL Server.

# **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Intermediate: Java, Basic: Javascript, TypeScript.

**Frameworks and Tools: Intermediate:** Spring framework, Spring boot, Sonar, Postman, Jira, JPA, Unit Test, Git, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, docker, Jenkins, PL-SQL, TypeScript, Azure devops, Oracle, RESTful APIs, JSON, XML, Hibernate, JWT, Apache Maven, Gradle, Github, Gitlab, bitbucket, Confluence, TFS, Swagger.

Languages: Intermediate English, Native Spanish.

## **EDUCATION**

Uniminuto University Corporation –Bello, Antioquia Financial Administration, September 2017 Metropolitan Technological Institute(ITM) –Medellín, Antioquia Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering, September 2014 Metropolitan Technological Institute(ITM) –Medellín, Antioquia System Technologist, July 2012